Hey there. Uh in this particular session
we are going to deep dive into uh the
module properties. Now these module
properties um are created uh when you
scan a particular module and uh these
are applicable for both module and the
module attributes. So uh these
properties are on the right side of your
window. So whenever I select any
particular module you will see uh the
details uh in the middle pane and then
on the right hand side you can see the
properties pane. Now if uh this is
collapsed uh you can expand this by
clicking on this arrow and then here you
will get all uh the module properties.
Now these model properties uh are
created by default
when you scan any particular control but
you can also um edit or create some of
these properties on your own.
So uh if you look at one of the module
attributes you will see these are again
the properties. So uh the module itself
will have uh some of its properties and
then the module attribute will have some
of the properties. So uh let's go
through some of uh these properties uh
what are these and uh how they can be
used uh when we are creating our
automation scripts and also we should
know what these properties are so that
when when we are working with different
types of controls uh we can work uh with
these properties. Now although there are
lots of different properties uh in a
module or module attribute uh I'm going
to go through some of the important ones
uh which uh we should know and also
which could be useful uh during our
automation. So the first one uh is the
automation framework. Now this
automation framework uh it basically
indicates which kind of framework you
are using. So either this could be the
Tbox uh which is uh the default uh
engine for the TSA and uh this is
already available when you install TSCA
right or it could be uh the generic
automation framework. Now this generic
automation framework is when you create
your own DLS and then you deploy them uh
into your TSA and then they are u
basically the generic controls which
you're using or which you have created
on your own. So these are the two types
of automation framework and then uh the
business type parameter. So this is uh
basically the technology specific root
element. So on the X module level this
indicates uh the root element. Now
either it could be HTML document or it
could be an XML document. So we will see
this uh when we look at an actual model
attribute and then uh the cardality. Now
this basically uh specifies how often uh
we will use a module attribute um as an
step value. Uh now by default it is only
one. Okay. So the cardality is defined
as 0 to one which means uh whatever step
value you have created uh could be used
just once. Now uh we can uh increase it.
So we can change it to 0 to n which
means uh uh this value uh could be used
uh n number of times. So example of this
we have already seen now in in our
previous sessions when we need a
particular attribute multiple times um
either it could be um a checkbox it
could be a button or anything right
which you want to perform an operation
on multiple times. So uh that you can do
using the cardality.
Then we have got the node path. Uh this
is the unique path of the object uh in
your workspace. So this sometimes you
would need to know where your object
lies in the workspace. Right?
And then we have got the synchronization
policy. Uh now this is basically uh the
policy which defines what is uh the
synchronization uh timeout for your uh
modules or module attributes. So we can
change this as well. The possible uh
values could be uh cannot be executed or
customizable default is on. Okay. So we
can do this uh synchronization enable or
disable using the settings. But here you
can define the policy for your module or
module attributes.
Then we have got the technical ID. Now
this is a parameter uh which is to
define a technology specific property.
Uh it will be mostly defined uh by TSKA
itself. And then we have got the unique
ID uh this is the unique identification
number uh in your workspace for your
particular object. So this will also be
defined by TSka and you can use it to
search your object in your workspace.
Then we have got the viewing group name.
U now this is the user group for whom
this particular object is visible. Uh
and you can always change this based on
whatever group you are giving
permissions or access to. So these are
some of the important properties. uh
some of them are automatically created
and some of them could be edited or
modified by you uh based on your
requirements.
Now if we compare whatever we have
discussed with an actual module
attribute uh and it properties uh so
these are all the properties okay so
some of them have the configuration uh
parameter or uh any other kind of
parameter which we'll discuss um in some
time but all these blue icons these are
the properties uh some of them have been
created already some of them is
modifiable some of them is not
modifiable which means You cannot modify
this right. So the node path you it will
give you the path of your object uh from
your workspace. So you can see from the
root element uh it is going to modules
and then the swag labs uh and then this
username right uh created by uh who has
created this object uh what time it was
created who modified it last time and
what time it was modified
um and then unique ID. So this is uh the
unique ID uh through which I can easily
search in uh my workspace. Okay.
Then uh business type uh so this is the
technology uh type of uh this particular
object. It is text box currently uh
that's why it is defined text box. Then
cardality we discussed uh this is
currently 0 to one. So it can only be
used once but I can change it to n.
Okay. And then uh it could be used
multiple times this particular module
attribute.
And then there are data type action mode
uh interface type uh which is uh GUI uh
which basically defines uh what kind of
interface you're using. So it could be
non GUI, it could be GUI or implicit.
and then the default value. Similarly
for module there are some properties
which we already discussed. So we
discussed about synchronization policy.
You can see these are the different
values. So default is on, default is
off, cannot be excluded uh or can not be
excluded for whole tree. Right? So
basically how you want to synchronize
your objects across your workspace.
That's what uh this property defines
and then the owning group name and the
the viewing group name. Um so these are
the two things which we can define
and then uh the technical ID. Uh this
doesn't have a technical ID but most of
the modules will have it. If it is
required TSA will grab it.
and then the business type which is the
HTML document and then the automation
framework which is TBOX currently.
So these are um all the properties. Um
as I said some of them you can modify
some of them you cannot but based on
your requirements you have to work out
some of these properties or you have to
modify them. So it's good to know what
properties uh generally are defined for
a particular module or a module
attribute. Now moving on uh we have
discussed about the default properties
but uh in addition to this uh your
modules or module attributes uh can also
use specific parameters and these
parameters um are defined uh in the
properties pane or they can be created
uh they are case sensitive and in TUSCa
the four major types of parameters are
configuration identification steering
and transition parameters.
So how do you get to these? So whenever
you select any particular module and go
to properties there you can create your
own params right. So when you right
click on this module you will see um
this uh the first option is to create a
module attribute.
Then uh we can create a configuration
parameter. We can create a transition
parameter. We can create a steering
parameter and then we can also create a
business ID parameter and then technical
ID parameter and then the reflected ID
parameter. Right? So this business
reflected um and the technical ID
parameter all combined they are
basically the identification parameters.
Okay. So these three uh are the
identification parameters. This is the
steering parameter. This is the
transition parameter and this is the
configuration parameter. Now if you look
at this module carefully uh you will see
that a configuration parameter is
already created uh which is called the
engine which is HTML and then we have
got three different steering parameters
here control framework enable slot
content handling and uh ignore area
controls.
So these are basically created by TSA
itself. So we haven't created this and
then we have got a technical ID
parameter which is title uh which is
using to basically identify or steer
this particular control u and it has got
a value right. So some of these
parameters TSCA will automatically
create in order to steer a particular
parameter. But then uh in some scenarios
where you are not able to identify or if
you're not able to steer a particular
control, you can also create your own
configuration steering uh or
identification parameters. Right? So
let's uh discuss little more about these
parameters now. So let's start with the
configuration parameters. Now what are
these? uh these parameters they define
which components uh should be used in
order to steer a particular control
right so some of the parameters so there
are lots of parameters again um you can
go through the whole list but these are
some of the important ones and which are
uh basically related to your web
controls now some of these parameters
could be specific to vision AI or could
be specific to a particular engine so
depends on which particular platform you
are working on. Uh you should be using
uh the specific configuration
parameters.
So uh let's look at some of them. So
first is constraint index.
Now this constraint index uh it is used
to specify the index which can uniquely
identify a particular control. So if you
have got multiple controls which have
got the same properties in a particular
web page and if you have to identify a
particular control then in this case you
can directly use the constraint index
you can put the index of that particular
control and it will be able to identify
it uh uniquely. Now the permissible
values for this particular parameter is
an integer. So you need to provide a
index.
Then we have got uh can execute in
parallel. Now this uh is basically for
parallel execution when you're working
with uh distributed execution. So you
have got dex agents where you want to
execute your tests parallelly and then
it is using the same module. So you want
to run it in two different test cases.
So in this kind of scenario you can um
change the value of this uh parameter
and it could be either true or false.
Then we have got the explicit name. Uh
now by default except value names cannot
be changed. Uh but if you set the value
of this property to true then you can
edit the name of the xstep value. Now uh
if you don't want to use uh the true or
false for this particular parameter, you
could also specify a value range for
this particular parameter. Right? So
this could be useful uh in some
scenarios uh where you want to
where you want to identify a particular
control using an explicit name.
Then uh we have got external engine. Uh
now this external engine is a parameter
for the mobile engine modules and uh it
it is mostly used for image based
automation.
Then we have got the algorithmic uh
association.
Now these are the specific parameter
which can be used for a search algorithm
in a selected context. Now target
objects uh are basically searched in the
context and then uh the logic of
algorithm search query could also be
used. Uh this is a very specific
scenario so I would not uh talk too much
about this.
Then we have got the special execution
task. Now using this parameter you can
perform specific tasks
u which could be used to steer your
control. Right? Then we have got the
technical association. Uh so this is a
specific parameter for the search
algorithm in the selected context. So a
property of a test object is directly
used at the context um so that it can
search an object easily. Okay. So it is
basically engine specific and we can see
this uh technical association in any of
our module or module attributes. Then we
have got the transition parameter. Well,
this can be used to transition between
technologies or contexts uh which could
allow various engines uh to be used uh
in the same uh test step. The value of
the name of the transition is used for
steering the control and it could
include some values like string property
to XML or X X path to XML element. So if
you're using uh XPath and then you want
to transition to an XML, you can do this
using this particular parameter. So
these are some of the parameters which
can be used uh in your module attribute.
So coming back here uh let's see how we
can create a configuration parameter for
maybe a module attribute right. So we
have to right click on the module
attribute in the properties pane and
then we need to select uh create
configuration parameter that will create
the parameter. You need to use a proper
name which uh we already discussed. So
for example I want to define the
explicit name. So I will say explicit
name. So it could be um true false or a
particular range. So I will enter true
here. So explicit name is true. I can
even create a constraint index here. So
if I create another configuration
parameter
and uh I name it constraint index.
Okay. And then um I can give it an index
of one.
So if there are multiple um controls
with this particular username uh it will
select this based on the constraint
index right and then I can even change
the name of this attribute. Okay. So for
example
when I create another test case here
and then I drag this
you will see I cannot change uh the
value of password and login because uh
they don't have an explicit name uh set
to true but I can change uh this name of
this particular module attribute which
is username I can keep it user right or
I can keep it email whatever uh whatever
value you want to put right so I can
change uh the name of this because I
have set a configuration parameter
explicit name equals to true so this is
how you can create configuration
parameters and this is how it can be
used to steer your controls uh in
specific scenarios where uh the generic
methods don't work. So now moving on u
let's talk about the identification
parameters. Now what are identification
parameters? They basically determine uh
which properties should be used to
search for a particular control to be
steered and you can combine any number
of parameters um using the and links.
Now there are three basic parameters uh
which we already saw when we looked at
the module attribute properties. So we
can create a business ID parameter and
this can be used with specific control
types. So these are the properties which
can be used uh with specific control
types and these are the same for all
technologies uh which you need to steer.
Okay. So for example uh each button has
the property label and each text box has
the property text. Okay. So uh you have
to use it accordingly. Then we have got
the reflected ID parameter. Now what are
this? So properties of test objects
which are not included uh by default uh
using TSA can be retrieved from uh the
target technology using reflection. So
the technology itself needs to support
the reflected object access. And one
thing to note here is if you are using
this time parameter then deflected ids
are generally slower uh when compared to
the default ids. Again it can be used
for a very specific scenario something
like um internet explorer which is out
of support. You can use this uh
parameter for the language attribute.
So then we have got the technical ID
parameter. This is the more common one.
Um it is provided by Tska for technology
specific controls. For example, value
for HTML input controls, inner text for
HTML elements, uh encoding for an XML
declaration and more. Right? So these
are all the different identification
parameters which uh can be used to
search a particular control.
Now if we come back here again, you will
see uh so we have got two technical ID
parameters. One is ID, one is tag and
then it has got specific values. Right?
So these are added by TSA for this
particular module attribute and uh
accordingly we can also create our own
um ID parameters as you can see. So I
can create a technical ID parameter. Uh
again I need to know what technical ID
I'm going to use and the value. Now
moving on to steering parameters. Uh
well steering parameters are generally
used to specify the behavior for a
control which is being steered and there
are multiple steering parameters. Some
of them are very specific to u specific
modules like vision AI uh or SAP modules
or other mobile engines. So there are
different types of uh steering
parameters but you need to use uh
depending on what type of control you
are trying to work with. Right? Some of
the important ones uh I have noted down
here which we can look at. So one is
bring to front parameter. Well this will
help you to uh bring the particular
window to the foreground by default.
Right now the default value is true. uh
but if you want to change it uh uh you
can change it to false which means it
will not allow the window to
automatically be brought to the
foreground right so it will run in the
background
then uh we have got the ignore indivis
then we have got the ignore invisible
HTML elements now this is again a very
specific scenario where in your
application you have got uh invisible
HTML elements
which uh will be present in your
application when you're doing the
execution now it might uh slow the
execution down. So what you can do you
can set the value to true and then TSA
will completely ignore these HTML
elements.
Then we have got the scrolling behavior.
Uh now this can be used to define the
control where you should position it on
the screen. Um the values for this is uh
top, bottom, center or none. So
basically uh once you put it on top it
will scroll from top. If you put it on
bottom it will scroll from bottom or
center or if you don't put anything it
will start from a particular position.
Right? So it's basically when you are
scrolling controls you can uh specify
the behavior of how you want to scroll
it.
Then we have got uh the send keys delay.
Now this can be used to specify a time
lag um where individual characters of a
keyboard command uh could be sent but
with a particular time delay. Right? For
example, I can set this to 100 uh which
means it will wait for 100 milliseconds
before it sends any keyboard commands
through my script.
Then we have got the synchronization
timeout. Um again uh we can tell toka
how long TSA wants to wait before uh it
looks out for a particular object or it
throws an exception. So you can set this
time out right here. You can do it in
the settings as well. You can do it
using a configuration parameter which
you can set in a test case. So there are
multiple ways of doing it and the same
uh for weight on you can also set a
steering parameter for that.
Then uh we have got this user
simulation. Now this is basically to
click events or keyboard commands uh
which can be triggered using the action
mode input. Now possible events could be
selecting or deselecting checkboxes or
radio buttons, pressing um selecting
links or entering text into text boxes.
Right? So you can either set the user
simulation to true or false. Um the
default is false. So if you want to do
any of these events uh in your
application, you can set the user user
simulation to true. So some of the
things which you're not able to do uh
through regular automation, you can do
using this particular steering
parameter. Then we have got to uh
different weight parameters. Wait after
and wait before. Now these two
parameters could be used to uh wait uh
until a particular time uh either before
or after the control is tiered. This
could be useful when you want to wait uh
before uh the application is ready or a
particular control is loading. So you
can use the wait after or wait before.
So these are all uh the different
steering parameters. Now if you come
back to Tuska and look at this module
attribute you can see um there is
already a steering parameter added which
is fire event and the value is set to
change. Okay. So similarly for password
and then login there is no steering
parameter and for this the module itself
we have got control framework set to
none. Uh we have got enable slot content
handling false and ignore area controls
false. Right. Again um I can go ahead
and add my own steering parameter.
Now we can add uh the weight before
and uh we can set the value to 10. Okay.
Right. So this will wait for 10
milliseconds before uh it is going to
perform any action on this particular
control which is the login button.
Right?
So this is how you can uh play around
with different types of parameters uh
which are the steering parameters. It is
basically used to help you uh steer your
controls and you can specify a
particular behavior of that particular
control before or after it is being
steered. Right.
The final type of uh parameter uh which
is present uh in TSA is the transition
parameter. It is not a very frequently
used parameter. uh as you can see here
this is the transition parameter and uh
we can use it as I said uh to transition
between technology or context. So if
you're working with uh mobile and x
browser engine uh you can set this
particular transition parameter and then
you can change your context from browser
to the mobile engine right and you can
use the same um parameter which is x
path. So I can use this for two
different technologies, right? Uh as I
said it is not very frequently used but
for very specific scenarios uh you can
also use this transition parameter.
So uh these are all the different
parameters uh and the properties for
your module attributes. Now although uh
the information is lot uh it is quite
important to understand what properties
you are working with and then what
properties you can change uh for your
controls or what additional parameters
which you can add for your controls so
that you can steer them um as per your
requirements.